好了 莉莉 11点上芭蕾课
Okay, Lily, ballet at 11:00,
之后和小伙伴一起玩 3点有空手道课
then a playdate, then karate class at 3:00,
你为什么不去拿训练服呢
so why don't you go get your uniform?
动作快点啦
Chop chop!
-小卡 -怎么了
- Cam. - What?
她在学空手道 这样说没什么
She's in karate. It's not offensive.
不一定 不过你为什么
Debatable, but why would you
要把这些课外活动
schedule all this extra stuff
跟她的才艺表演安排在同一天呢
on the same day as her talent show?
你是在批评我给我们的音盲女儿
Okay, are you accusing me of overscheduling
安排过满 导致她累得
our tone-deaf daughter so she's so tired
错过了才艺表演 而没有丢人现眼吗
she misses the talent show and doesn't humiliate herself?
莉莉没有什么才能
Lily has no talent.
因为她才7岁 没有人7岁时就有才能
Because she's 7. No one has talent at 7.
我就有 多得很
I did. Tons of it.
薅羊毛 剥玉米 捆干草
Sheep-shearing, cornhusking, hay-baling.
我第一次参加小王子选美时
It was hard for me to pick just one to showcase
都不知道该选哪个做才艺展示
at my first little prince pageant.
最后我跳了华尔兹
In the end, I went with waltzing.
你7岁就跳华尔兹
You waltzed at 7?
差不多吧 我搭档有两只左蹄
Barely. My partner had two left hooves.
我拿到了
I got it!
等等 我的才艺表演不是今天吗
Hey, wait. Isn't my talent show today?
谁知道呢 我们去骑小马吧
Oh, who knows? But let's go ride some ponies.
不不不 你说得对 就是今天
No, no, you're right. It is today,
既然还要过会儿才上芭蕾课
and since you have a little bit of time before ballet...
你们俩何不热热身呢
Why don't you two do a little bit of warming up?
大师 来吧
Maestro? Come on.
-好 太好了 谢谢 -来吧
- Oh, okay, great. Thank you. - Yeah, yeah.
莉莉 你能跟我一起唱*C*
So, Lily, can you meet me here at... *C*
*C*
*你没有跟上大爸*
*Now daddy's lonely*
*我跟上你了*
*I'm there with you*
*不 你没有 差得远呢*
*No, you're not, you're not even close*
*你听自己唱的也完全不一样吧*
*This can't possibly sound the same to you*
*也许我能帮帮忙 小爸也来唱*
*Maybe I can help, daddy is also here at...*
*C*
*不 这都不是一个音符*
*No, that's not even a note*
*我觉得你是故意的*
*I feel like you're doing it on purpose*
*这话有点刻薄[音有点高]*
*That seems a little bit sharp*
*我从不走音 我是完美音准*
*I'm never sharp, I'm pitch-perfect*
*我是说你对我们女儿的语气*
*I'm talking about your tone toward our daughter*
*就算你们是用唱的 我也能听懂*
*I can understand you even when you're singing*
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要把屋子里的所有奶嘴都收起来
I am gathering every binky that is in this house,
因为从今天起 乔要开始戒奶嘴了
because from today on, Joe is going cold turkey.
好了乔 你可以最后再吸一口
Okay, Joe, have your last puff if you want.
歌洛莉亚 我在看节目呢
Gloria, I'm trying to watch something here.
好 你想哭可以接着哭
Okay, you can keep crying all you want.
我什么都听不到 试试在哥伦比亚长大
I can't hear anything. Try growing up in Colombia.
我的奶嘴只是个火花塞
My binky was a spark plug.
卢克 你怎么能忘了你的泳裤
Luke, how could you forget your bathing suit?
你是来游泳的
You came over here to swim.
没事啦 亲爱的 他可以穿我的
It's all right, honey. He can wear mine.
我可以跟杰借
I'll borrow from Jay.
有哪个你最爱的是我不能碰的吗 杰
You have a favorite I should keep my hands off of, Jay?
早在20年前就被你碰了
That ship sailed about 20 years ago.
说得好
Zinger!
把这种魅力
Save some of that charm
留到拍广告的时候再用吧 老爸
for our commercial shoot today, dad, huh?
你看到对手是怎么做的了吗
You see what our competition's doing?
看到那些滤镜 特效吗
See the lasers? Special effects?
我打赌他们在那玩意上花了五百万
I'll bet they spent 5 million bucks on that thing.
别担心 老爸
Don't worry, dad.
我想出来的创意比他们的好多了
The concept I came up with is so much better than theirs.
我们得放弃
We're scrapping it.
什么 我为那个努力了两个月
What? I worked for two months on that.
抱歉 我们得用证明确有成效的东西
Sorry. We gotta go with what's proven.
重拍我以前的广告
We're remaking my old commercial.
三十年前 我爸在本地登了一则
30 years ago, my dad was in a local ad
普里契特橱柜的广告
for Pritchett's Closets,
他一直为
and he has always been
他想出来的广告语自豪
really proud of the slogan he came up with.
我一直都不懂是什么意思
I've never understood what it means.
普里契特橱柜
Pritchett's Closets --
选择我们的九大奢华样板
Choose one of our nine luxurious models
例如蒙特卡罗
like the Monte Carlo.
或者采用顶尖技术
Or how about a custom design
制造的专属定制衣柜
using our state-of-the-art technology?
来普里契特
Come visit Pritchett's
把梦想橱柜带回家
and go home with the closet of your dreams.
买橱柜吗 你会爱上它
Closet? You'll love it!
整个市区都为那则广告疯狂了
The entire town went nuts for that ad.
人们在街上拦住我
People stopped me in the street,
让我再说一遍那条广告语
asking me to say the slogan.
你确定他们不是在让你解释清楚吗
Are you sure they weren't asking you to explain it?
有什么好解释的
What's to explain?
把"喜欢它吗 你会爱上它"
Instead of "Like it? You'll love it,"
改成"买橱柜吗 你会爱上它"
you use the word "Closet."
那何不说"喜欢它吗 你会买橱柜"
Then why not, "Like it? You'll closet!"?
那样说不通
That makes no sense.
听着 我知道有一个出名的的老爸
Look, I know it was rough on you and Mitch
让你和米奇很痛苦
having a famous dad,
在饭店里被拍照
you know, getting your picture taken in restaurants.
只有一次 老爸 只是因为你跟
That happened one time, dad. Only because you were
车库门遥控器之王拉尔夫·伯曼在一起
with Ralph Berman, "Garage door opener king."
是他跟我们在一起
Hey, he was eating with us.
重点是
The point is,
那则广告很成功 也会再次成功的
that ad scored for us, and it will again.
所以就要放弃我的全部努力
So we're gonna flush all my hard work
就因为你被那个都称不上朗朗上口的
because you got freaked out by some commercial
广告歌给吓到了吗
that's not even that catchy.
*衣柜衣柜*
*Closets, closets*
好了 进去
All right, get there!
如果你真想等贝丝来了之后 让她感动
Hey, if you really wanna impress Beth when she gets here,
你应该试试赢那只大象
you should try for that giant elephant.
企鹅也不错
Oh, penguin's just as good.
进了
Money!
我花了很多钱 很多
I just spent a lot of money. A lot.
抱歉 有点工作上的事
Sorry. I had to check in at the job.
店里总是有事
Always something going down at the Hut.
你在the Hut上班啊
You work at the Hut?
我本想猜必胜客
I would guess pizza,
但是根据当你帮我从游览船上
but based on your ripply stomach I saw
下来时我看到的你平坦的腹部
when you helped me get down off the gondola ride,
我猜是 墨镜客
I'm gonna guess... Sunglass Hut.
是啊 蔡斯挑了这副古董墨镜
Yep, Chase picked out these vintage-y sunglasses
我戴起来看上去像是在70年代的
that look like I could've been murdered
酷炫派对上会被谋杀的对象
at a cool house party in the '70s.
你被陷害了[加了外框]
Ooh, you've been framed.
你该用这句
You should use that.
你在墨镜客工作时可以用
At your job at the Hut.
你刚说了赫特人贾巴[音似]
You just said "Jabba the Hut."
我真的搞不懂了 两位
I'm really lost here, guys.
真疼
That smarts.
-又来吗 -是啊 可能只是晕动病
- Again? - Yeah. Uh, it's probably just motion sickness.
是啊 动作是整天往嘴里塞
Uh, yeah, the motion of shoving deep fried garbage
油炸垃圾食品
in your mouth all day.
又是我经理 她总是盯着我
It's my manager again. She's always on me.
等不及到秋天她去上大学的时候了
Can't wait till the fall when she's off to college.
什么事 莫琳
Yeah, Maureen?
贝丝不来了
Beth's not coming.
她太累了 不想从圣地亚哥一路开过来
She's too tired to drive up from San Diego.
这个我从来没见过的贝丝
So this Beth, who I've never actually met,
她是真正的活生生的姑娘吗
is she one of those real-life move-around girls?
她是真正的姑娘
No, she is a real girl.
好吧 但她都大老远飞来
Fine, but, you know, she flew all the way over here
进行海岸警卫队训练了
for some coast guard training.
她都没法开几小时车来见你吗
She can't drive a couple hours to see you?
她一早上都在拯救溺水的人体模型
She's been saving drowning mannequins all morning,
有些是特大号的
and some of them are plus-sized,
因为很多人是从游艇上掉下来
because a lot of people fall off cruise ships.
好吧 但她都放了你一百次鸽子了
Okay, but doesn't it bother you
你难道就不觉得不爽吗
that she's flaked for, like, the hundredth time?
我知道你不喜欢贝丝
I know you have a problem with Beth,
但我俩的关系在我看来挺好 好吗
but what we have works for me, okay?
如果我们要进行指责[伸出手指]
And if we're pointing fingers...
我需要你帮我找钥匙
I want you to help me find my keys.
等等
Wait. Shh.
-在我的外套里 -好吧
- They're in my jacket. - Okay.
知道了
Got it.
妈妈 那个变态又在盯着你看了
Mom, that perv is ogling you again.
没有 我在读星座运势
No! I was reading my horoscope.
"你今天会借一件超大的泳衣" 什么
"You will borrow a huge swimsuit today." What?
不 是飞机
Ay, no, the plane!
那架飞机 总是在偷窥我
The plane! It's always spying on me!
走开 不然我要报警了
Go away or I'm gonna call the policeman!
别浪费时间 歌洛莉亚
Wow, don't even waste your time, Gloria.
警察可搞不定用这种飞机的人
Johnny Law's got no chance with that baby.
这是一架云端凝视机
You're looking at a freeling cloudgazer
配备后市倒频器 无法追踪
with after-market frequency scrambler. Untraceable.
你大概能猜出 我也是无人机爱好者
As you can guess, I'm a droner myself.
是啊 你现在就在嗡嗡嗡
Yes, you're droning right now.
越来越近了
Ay, it's getting closer!
妈妈 也许你该盖住身子
Mom, maybe you should cover up.
不 那太疯狂了
No! That's crazy.
我们可以把它打下来
We can just knock it out of the sky.
曼尼 拿着水管
Manny, grab the hose.
我来弄瞎它
I'll use this to blind it.
我的眼睛
My eyes!
就那样 它消失了
And just like that, it disappears.
帮他说句话 水真的很冷
In his defense, the water's really cold.
你们还在排练啊
You're still rehearsing.
是啊 我们为莉莉的歌喉找到了
We sure are, and we found a more appropriate song
一首更合适的歌
for Lily's singing voice.
真的吗 我很想听听
Really? Well, I'd love to hear it.
好啊
Okay.
*每个人都是功夫高手* *是的*
*Everybody was kung fu fighting* *We are*
*飞蹴疾如闪电* *是的*
*Those kicks were fast as lightning* *We are*
*尽管这有些惊险* *是的*
*In fact, it was a little bit frightening* *We are*
好了 停下 打住 打住
Okay, stop, stop, stop.
不 拜托 不行
No, come on. No. No!
太荒唐了 她都没在唱歌
This is ridiculous. She's not even singing.
她之前也没在唱啊
She wasn't singing before either.
好吧 去喝点水
Okay, go get some water.
-小卡 -米奇尔 我不想要她
- Cam. - Mitchell, I just don't want her to embarrass herself
在她朋友面前出丑 还有家长呢
in front of her friends, not to mention the parents.
我都能听见安德鲁居高临下的"嗯"了
I can already hear Andrew's condescending, "Hmm."
天啊 你还在跟安德鲁斗呢
Oh, my gosh. You're still competing with Andrew.
他发动了政变 米奇尔
He staged a coup, Mitchell.
他把我赶出了我建立的组织 我建立的
He forced me out of the group I founded.I founded it.
绿袖是加州南部
The Greensleevers were Southern California's
最棒的假日合唱团
premier holiday chorus
12月23日的《洛杉矶时报》
and "Just the nutmeg we want
称我们为 搭配圣诞季蛋酒的
our yuletide eggnog dusted with"
-最佳肉豆蔻 -我记得
- "L.A. Times," December 23, 199... - I remember.
我记得 我记得
Oh, I remember. I remember.
你担心的不是莉莉自己丢脸
So you're not worried about Lily embarrassing herself.
而是莉莉让你丢脸
You're worried about Lily embarrassing you.
既然她不唱歌了 就不会丢脸了
Not so much now that she's not singing.
莉莉想唱什么就唱什么
Lily is gonna sing whatever she wants,
你不能再和安德鲁比来比去了
and you're gonna get over this thing with Andrew...
因为成年人不该有冤家
Because a grown man should not have a nemesis.
-太荒唐了 -你知道什么才荒唐吗
- It's ridiculous. - You know what's ridiculous?
是被迫把圣诞铃铛
Is being forced to turn in your jingle bells
交给一个音域还不如茶壶广的人
to a man with less vocal range than a teakettle.
我还以为你有约会呢
Oh, I thought you had a date.
是啊 但我不去了 他不怎么聪明
I did, but I bailed. He's not exactly the sharpest shed.
他怎么了
What is his deal?
我几小时前拿走了他的安抚奶嘴
I took his pacifier hours ago,
他还在哭呢 真是个娇气包
and he's still crying. He's being such a baby.
也许他还没准备好放弃奶嘴
Well, maybe he's just not ready to give them up.
不 我跟我妈保证过 他不会再用了
No, I promised my mother that he wouldn't use it anymore.
他叔叔四岁才停止使用奶嘴
Her uncle used it until he was 4,
现在他进了监狱
and now he's in jail.
感觉你家的很多故事都是那样结束的
I feel like a lot of your family stories end that way.
我要去换泳衣了
I'm gonna put on a bathing suit.
曼尼
Hi, Manny.
把乔放在电视机前
Please stick Joe in front of the TV.
每次他听到那首广告歌就会安静下来
He always calms down when he listens to...
*衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜*
Closets, closets, closets, closets.
爸 你得看看这个
Dad, you might wanna see this.
他把我们放到YouTube上了
He put us on YouTube?
视频名字叫"无人机对战傻瓜 1比0"
He called it "Drone 1, idiots zero."
有三万两千浏览量了
It has 32,000 views.
我们要反击
We have to strike back.
这无人机惹错傻瓜了
That drone just messed with the wrong idiot.
安迪进医院了
Andy's in the hospital.
不是吧 怎么搞的
What? Why?
阑尾炎
Appendicitis.
他没事吧 我是不是该去看看他
Is he okay? Maybe I should go down there.
这可不好
This is not good.
我二表弟得过阑尾炎
My second cousin got appendicitis,
结果现在进监狱了
and now he's in jail.
买橱柜吗 你会爱上它
Closet? You'll love it.
好的 卡
And... cut.
很不错 杰
Uh, that was great, Jay.
我们再试一次 可能要稍微轻快一点
Let's try it again. Maybe a little lighter.
轻快一点
Lighter.
对 开心点 温馨点
Yeah. Just, you know, happier, warmer.
这还不够
Even more?
好吧
All right.
杰的部分 准备
From Jay's line. Here we go. And...
开拍
Action.
买橱柜吗 你会爱上它
Closet? You'll love it!
卡
Cut.
你也觉得跟刚才完全一样对吧
You see that was exactly the same, right?
是的
I do.
-那句话什么意思 -我不知道
- So what does it mean? - I don't know.
满意了吗
So do we have it?
我都录了十个不同版本了
I gave you, like, 10 different choices.
别想太多了 随便挑一个用吧
Let's not overthink this, huh? Just pick one.
好吧 给他点时间
Okay. Well... give him a minute.
-他会冷静的 -好
- He'll calm down. - Sure.
-克莱尔 -来了
- Uh, hey, Claire? - Yes. Yeah.
我们聊了一下
So we were just talking,
仅仅从市场营销角度来看
and strictly from a marketing standpoint,
-你觉不觉得杰有点 -糟糕
- do you think Jay is, um... - He stinks.
他简直太差了 真不幸
He's the worst. So bad.
但是从保住工作的角度讲
And, um... strictly from a keeping-my-job standpoint,
你要是能告诉他就太好了
it would be so dope if you told him that.
天呐 我炒不了我爸
Oh, God. I can't fire my dad!
我知道这很不容易
I know. I know. It must be hard,
但你也知道这对公司最好
but you realize it's the best thing for the company.
-是的 -好吧
- Yes, I do. - Okay.
你会支持我的对吧
Can I at least count on you to back me up?
当然 拜托 我们都知道你爸很棒
Totally. Come on. We both know your dad is incredible.
你今天看到他了吗 就像乔治·克鲁尼
Do you see him today? He's like George Clooney
比他老 但是更帅
but older, but better.
我还以为那是杰 抱歉
I... thought that was Jay. I'm sorry.
吓死我了
Oh, man. Almost fainted.
我要在两腿之间挖个洞把自己埋起来
Just gonna put my head between my legs.
那里空间很充足啊
Plenty of room down there.
我们要暂时休息一下 把彩纸屑扫一扫
We'll now take a break to sweep up the confetti
带妆彩排的时候可没说会用这个
that was definitely not mentioned in dress rehearsal.
好吧 安德鲁来了
Okay, here comes Andrew.
我们要装出一副
Just act like we don't care
不在乎绿袖合唱团事件的样子
about the whole Greensleevers thing.
希望我能做到
Ooh, I hope I could pull this off.
卡梅伦
Cameron.
安德鲁
Andrew.
表演挺有意思的
Enjoyable show.
-是你 -导演吗 今年不是我
- So did you... - Direct? No, not this year.
我也觉得不是
Ah, I didn't think so.
你...
You're...
我们也很喜欢这场演出
So we're really enjoying the show, too.
孩子们是主角
it's all about the kids, you know.
抱歉 他们只有不带气的
Sorry. They only had flat.
米奇尔
Mitchell.
西蒙
Simon.
没想到 安德鲁最近跟西蒙结婚了
Turns out recently, Andrew married Simon.
我在法学院的死敌
My bitter rival from law school.
或者说 冤家
Or... nemesis?
我已经
I've...
工作怎么样
So how's work?
你一定知道我现在是
I'm sure you heard I made partner
戈麦弗亚勒律所的合伙人了
at Gotshal, Manges, Flom, Arps&LeBoeuf.
我进了司法部门
And I'm actually at the justice institute now.
特别好
So rewarding.
我们公司好像
Oh, I think our firm donated
把一台旧传真机捐给你们了
one of our old fax machines to you guys.
我们得走了 要往前坐一点
We better go. We're moving closer
因为我们的女儿要表演了
because our daughter's about to perform.
你女儿是从越南领养的 对吧
Yours is from Vietnam, right?
我们从韩国领养了一个
We were able to adopt one from Korea.
所以吧...
So...
他刚刚用"所以吧"来结束对话的吗
Did he really just end a conversation on "So..."?
我们赶紧坐下吧
Let's just take our seats.
不 小卡 我不知道
No, Cam, I-I don't know if this is
这种环境是不是对莉莉有帮助
the most supportive environment for Lily to --
-我同意 我们带她出去吧 -好
- I agree. Let's get her out of the show. - Okay. Yeah.
韩国人基因真的比较好吗
And are Koreans really better?
我不知道
I don't know.
猎物上钩了
Chicken's in the pot.
重复一次 目标出现
I repeat, we have eyes on the chicken.
吃我一弹 该死 没打中
Eat paint. Damn it. I missed.
卢克 地心引力
Luke, gravity!
闭嘴 书呆子
Shut up, nerd!
B计划 如果你打不过 上无人机
Plan "B"! If you can't beat 'em, drone 'em!
启动声控
Activate voice control!
前进十英尺
Forward 10 feet.
有敌袭 快卧倒
Oh! It's attacking! Get down!
该死 解除声控
Damn it. Deactivate voice control!
C计划 跟它回家
Plan "C"! Follow it home!
快点
Hurry up!
那是我的单车
Hey! That's my bike!
我们都做出了牺牲
We're all making sacrifices!
我穿的是单片女士泳装
I'm wearing a monokini!
莉姿
Hey, Lizzie!
我得借用一下这个
Okay, I need to borrow this, okay?
给我 好的 好
Here, just -- all right. Okay.
我一定会还给你的
I promise to bring it back, all right?
你拿走我妈的加湿器时也是这么说的
No, that's what you said about my mom's humidifier!
它朝河那边飞去了 想甩掉我们
He's heading for the river to try and lose us.
都赖你 专利局的丹尼丝
Damn you, Denise, at the patent office
拒绝给我的水下自行车提供专利
for stalling my auqabike!
小心
Look out!
你还好吧
You okay?
要打倒我 一辆小小卡车可不够
It's gonna take more than a little truck to st--
-你们没事吧 -没事
- Are you guys okay? - Yeah.
这事没完 你心里清楚
This isn't over yet! You know that!
天呐 老爸
Oh, God! Dad!
菲尔
Phil!
"无人机对战傻瓜 2比0"
"Drone 2, idiots zero."
拜托
Come on!
至少离得很远 看不清是我们
At least it's far away so you can't tell it's us.
是啊
Yeah.
又有一条新评论
Oh, great. Another comment.
"大笑 那是我的地产商 菲尔"
"LOL. That's my realtor, Phil D--"
叫上她走吧
Okay, let's just grab her and go.
再下一个就是她了
She's up after the next act.
我们这么做没错
Hey, we're doing the right thing.
人在7岁就能形成重大的心理创伤了
You can develop deep emotional scars at age 7.
我到现在都吃不了
I still can't eat--
盐醋味薯片 我知道
Salt and vinegar chips. Yes, I know.
我现在没空跟你回想过去
I can't relive this with you right now.
抱歉
I'm sorry. Okay.
看看她
Look at her.
是啊 原来她连用嘴接东西都不会
Yeah. Add mouth-catching to things she can't do.
不是这个 她完全不紧张
No. I mean, she's not nervous at all,
看看其他的孩子 他们都慌得不行
and look at the other kids. They're a wreck.
也许她没有继承我们的天赋
You know, she may not have gotten our talent,
但她也没有我们这么在意别人的看法
but she didn't get our self-consciousness either.
这一点我们还是不要强加给她了
Well, we're not giving her our self-consciousness.
今天是她的大好日子 而她
Today is her day, and she is--
她要唱歌 来吧
she is gonna sing. Come on.
大家好 我妈妈在做化疗
Hi, my mom's doing chemo,
所以我剃了头发 看起来和她一样
so I shaved my head to be like her.
这首歌献给你 妈妈
This is for you, mom.
*而我*
*And I*
*我*
*I*
*会一直爱你*
*Will always love you*
有麻烦了
Hey, hey, we got a problem.
怎么了 宝贝
What's wrong, sweetie?
-我不能在她后面唱啊 -你没搞错吧
- I can't go after her. - Are you kidding?
亲爱的 我们不能就这样走了
Okay, well, honey, we can't just leave right now.
我们得走了 玛娅有点发烧
Sorry, gotta run. Maya's feeling a bit feverish.
看来有些人受不了激烈的赛况啊
Oh, well, I guess some people can't take the heat.
*会一直爱你*
*Will always love you*
-你信吗 -当然不信
- Can you believe that? - No.
行了 撤吧 从偏门出去
Okay, now we can leave. Let's go out the side door.
老爸 我
Hey, dad, I--
我试着在拍摄之后找你
I tried to grab you after the shoot,
但你就那么消失了
but you just flew out of there.
我不想看起来好像要
I didn't want it to seem like
留在那里听你们的赞美
I was hanging around for compliments.
你走之后我们讨论了一下
There, there was some discussion after you left.
去别家吧 小伙子
Keep it moving, buddy!
有几个人觉得你有些
A-a few people feel that you came across a little--
牌子上写了"不要乱发小广告"
Sign says "No menus"!
你刚才说什么
What'd you say?
大家都觉得
The group thinks
如果换一个代言人
that maybe it would be for the best
会对公司有好处
if, if someone else was our spokesman.
公司名叫普利契特衣柜
It's called Pritchett's Closets.
我知道 但有时候你有点
Yeah, I know, but you were coming off
-就一丁点 -这些小混蛋
- just a tiny bit - Damn kids.
球现在是我的了
It's mine now!
-有点暴躁 -暴躁
- Tiny bit grumpy. - Grumpy?
凶一点没什么关系
There's nothing wrong with being a little gruff.
这就是你的性格
That's how you are.
-但在销售方面 老爸 -你说什么
- But when it comes to selling, dad-- - What do you mean?
你说"我的性格"是什么意思
What do you mean, how I am?
大家就是这么看我的 觉得我很凶吗
Is that what people think of me, that I'm some big grump?
老爸 你不会这么惊讶吧
Dad, that cannot be a big shock
毕竟孩子们都叫你"暴脾气外公"
that kids call you "Grumpa."
从什么时候开始的
Since when?
他们居然没当着你面说
Not to your face?
胆小鬼
Cowards.
如果我是"暴脾气"
So if I get "Grumpa,"
菲尔他爸又得了个什么称呼
what do they call Phil's dad?
"欢乐多"
You know, just "Funpa."
那个蠢货居然叫"欢乐多"
That mound of human silly string gets "Funpa"?
这不是重点
That's not the issue, dad.
我知道重点是什么
No, no, I know what the issue is.
你是说我不近人情
You're saying I'm not warm and cuddly enough
不适合卖衣柜
to sell closets anymore.
所有父亲都预见到这天
It's a day that every father knows may come
但他们都希望这天永不会来
but hopes it never will.
你确定所有的父亲
Are we sure every father--
别说了
Stop hurting me!
你感觉怎么样
Hey, how you feeling?
看起来手术前
Oh, looks like they got you
他们给你下了不少猛药啊
on a bunch of good drugs before your surgery.
我就是来看看你
I just came in to check on you.
你一个人经历这些肯定很害怕吧
Pretty scary going through this all by yourself.
你女朋友不在真是太可怜了
Too bad your girlfriend couldn't be here.
贝丝是真人
Beth is real.
我知道
I know that.
不
No.
贝丝是真人
Beth is real.
好吧 你真的想谈谈吗
Okay, you really wanna talk about it?
你们俩的关系又有多真呢
How real is your relationship?
真的感情是当某人发现你进了医院
Real is when someone finds out that you're in the hospital
她会放下所有事赶来 因为她不想
and drops everything because she doesn't want you
让你一个人承受这一切
to be freaked out and alone.
我不想伤害你
Look, I'm not trying to be mean.
只是你有没有想过
It's just, you ever think you might be
你可能太委屈自己了呢
settling for something here?
我们都做过这种事
We've-we've all done it.
跟自己说企鹅也挺好的
Talked ourselves into the penguin
因为觉得自己得不到大象
because we didn't think we had a shot at the elephant.
如果我就是你的大象
If I'm your elephant,
你是可以追到我的
you have a shot.
我想说的就是这个 傻瓜
That's what I'm trying to say, dummy.
他终于睡着了 真好
I'm glad he's finally asleep.
他进来以后一直在喊贝丝·以姿丽
He kept going on about Beth Israel in hospital.
我跟他说了他的保险没问题
I told him his insurance is fine.
我们可以在这里做手术
We can do the surgery here.
贝丝·以姿丽
Beth Israel?
天呐 安迪 你还好吗
Oh, my god. Andy, are you okay?
他没事吧
He's okay, right?
是的 他在睡觉
Uh, yeah, he's sleeping.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我是贝丝 安迪的女朋友
I'm Beth, Andy's girlfriend.
你好 我是海莉
Oh. Hi. Uh, Haley.
是你啊
Of course.
安迪跟我说了很多关于你的事
Andy's told me so much about you.
很抱歉没赶上嘉年华
I'm so sorry about missing the carnival.
我已经连续两天没睡觉了
I've just been up for two days straight.
既然你来了 那我就先走了
Well, you're here, so I should go.
好的 谢谢你
Okay. Thanks again.
你听 你听
Listen, listen.
起作用了 他不哭了
It worked. He stopped crying.
真好 我很高兴 听我说
Oh, so good for him. I'm glad. So listen.
这些帅哥靓妹是谁啊
Who are these beautiful people?
一定是你的表亲吧
They must be cousins of yours?
是的 他们是...
Yes, they are --
等一下
Wait a minute.
你把它关掉了
You turned it off.
我还以为他终于不再想要他的奶嘴了呢
And I thought that he was finally getting over his binky!
哭声简直要让我发狂了
The screaming is driving me crazy!
那哭声让每个人都要发狂了 歌洛莉亚
The screaming is driving everyone crazy, Gloria.
要么你把这个关掉
You either have to turn this thing off,
要么我就到楼上去
or I'm going up there
把我的钥匙给他含着
and giving him my keys to suck on.
我美丽的太太今天怎么样
Hey-o! How's my beautiful wife?
发生什么事了 你为什么这副表情
What happened? Why do you look like that?
我只是很高兴见到你
I'm just happy to see you.
你看起来像个疯子
You look like a crazy person.
爸 你对你的脸做了什么 说吧
Dad, what are you doing with your face? Come on.
没有人发现乔已经不哭了吗
Did anyone else notice that Joe stopped crying?
没看完才艺表演就回来了 别问为什么
Back from the talent show early. Don't ask why.
我喜欢看孩子们的才艺表演
I love it when children have talent.
你为什么要那样笑
Why are you smiling like that?
是不是妈妈出什么事了
Did something happen to mom?
把你的脸恢复成原来的样子
Put your face back to what it used to be.
拜托 爸爸 别这样
Come on, dad. Just drop it.
所以现在我又太开心了
So now I'm too happy.
你们到底想怎么样
Make up your damn minds!
这样才对嘛
There he is.
我来解决
I've got it.
爸爸 对不起 我并不是想让你心烦
Dad, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to upset you.
省省吧 克莱尔
Save it, Claire.
我看了今天我们拍的片子
I watched what we shot today.
没错 我已经不再是30年前
Yeah, I'm not that cheery,
那个快乐 可爱的名人了
likeable celebrity I was 30 years ago.
我现在是个臭脾气老头
I am an old grump now.
我什么时候变成这样的
When did I turn that corner?
你没有 你没有
You haven't. You haven't.
我是说 你在慢慢变成那样
I mean, you're creeping up to it.
你开了转向灯了 不过还没有转弯
You got your blinker on, but...you haven't yet.
我在我爸爸身上看到过这种变化
I saw it happen to my dad, you know?
前一天 他还是乐天派的旋转钻机操作员
One day, hap-go-lucky rotary drill operator,
第二天他就把啤酒瓶扔到电视机上了
the next he's rowing his Schlitz at the TV
就因为体育节目解说员是女的
'cause some lady sportscaster came on.
我曾发誓永远不要变成他那样
I swore I'd never be like that.
你没那么糟 如果你真那么糟
You're not that bad. If you were,
我们怎么会没事都到你这里来呢
why would we all spend all our time over here?
你们来就是为了去泳池游泳
Oh, you just come here for the pool.
才不是... 才不是那样
That's not...That's not true.
不 才不是呢
No. Crazy.
爸爸 你离变成爷爷那样还远着呢
Dad, you are a long way from turning into grandpa.
知道吗 他第一次
You know, I was with him
在超市看到寿司时 我跟他在一起
the first time he saw sushi in the grocery store.
他拿起结账用的扫码器
He grabbed the price check mic
给我们做了关于日本偷袭珍珠港的演讲
and treated us all to a little lecture on Pearl Harbor.
你只需要再努力一些就可以了
You just have to fight it a little.
感谢你这样说 宝贝
I appreciate it, honey.
我不太确定
I'm not sure some of this
可能这就是自然规律
just isn't natural order of things.
敌人在十点钟方向 行动起来
Bogey at 10:00! Move it!
这不是训练
This is not a drill!
什么
What?
先生们 听我倒数
Gentlemen, on my count,
让我们释放战争恶魔
let slip the dogs of war!
你们三个在这儿干什么呢
What the hell are you three doing out here?!
我们如果想成功的话
Now if we have a prayer at this thing,
必须呈三角形站好
we have to triangulate.
菲尔 你站着别动
Phil, stay where you are.
卢克 站到树旁 给我几个橙子
Luke, by the tree. Give me some of those oranges.
给你
Here you go.
现在听我倒数
Now let's go on my count,
没有人会从8开始数
'cause nobody starts at 8.
让那玩意滚出我家草坪的领空
Get the hell off the space above my lawn!
看看哪 快看
Take a look at this. Look at this.
我们做到了
We did it!
我们成功了
无人机对战傻瓜 2比1
Drone 2, idiots 1!
有时候男孩子们需要一点帮助
Some boys need a little help,
但不是所有男孩
but not all boys.
没有奶嘴
No binky.
好了 爸 我们准备好了
All right, dad, we're ready for you.
就给我们五分钟
Just give us five minutes.
感觉像是在浪费时间 不过开始吧
Seems like a waste of time, but go ahead.
衣柜 不过没有雪茄
Closet, but no cigar.
为什么 因为我们藏起来了
Why? Because we closet.
我要她藏起来的东西
I'll have what she's closet.
妈妈总说
Mama always said
生活就像一盒衣柜
life is like a box of closets.
各就各位 预备 衣柜
On your mark, get set, closet.
让我们准备好迎接衣柜
Let's get ready to closet!
跟我的小衣柜打声招呼吧
Say hello to my little closet.
见鬼 都很不错
Damn it. They all good.